FAVOUR ISIOMA IYAMA

Address: Mafias Quarters, Yola South, Adamawa, Nigeria. | Email: isiomaiyama@gmail.com

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/favour-iyama-48ba501b5

Contact: +2348168982358, +2349071689676

SUMMARY STATEMENT

Adept at working with data with over five years of experience. Meticulous in collecting, entering, and analyzing data with a strong commitment to accuracy and efficiency. Proficiency in data entry software and tools such as MS Excel, LAMISplus, SurveyCTO, Google Forms; and data analysis software such as MS Excel, Power BI, and SQL. I excel in entering, verifying, and maintaining data while adhering to data quality standards. Exhibits strong organizational skills and the ability to work independently or as part of a team.

EXPERIENCE

DATA ENTRY CLERK (DEC)/ DATA ANALYST | Achieving Health Nigeria Initiative (AHNi)

Feb 2024 - July 2024

Duties

- Analyzing the data collected on various indicators such as PrEP, PMTCT, HTS, CXCA etc.
- Data quality management, ensuring there is concurrence with the PMM tools and EMR.
- Reviewing the entries on Daily Performance Tracker (DPT) on the database
- Retrieving results, or any information on a client from the database, Lamis, and Excel when required.
- Monthly Summary Report on ART, TBT, PMTCT, HTS, PrEP.

DATA ENTRY CLERK (DEC) VOLUNTEER | Achieving Health Nigeria Initiative (AHNi)

July 2023 - Jan 2024

Duties

- Entry of data collected by on PrEP and PEP treatment, enrolment, ART refill and other information to the Database, Lamis, and Microsoft Excel.
- Cross-checking, reviewing, and validating the data source for inaccuracy, and anomalies.

- Entering data into a provided template spreadsheet on Microsoft Excel.
- Inputting entries on Daily Performance Tracker (DPT) on the database
- Updating information to an already existing entry on the Database, Lamis, and Excel when new data is provided.
- Retrieving results, or any information on a client from the database, Lamis, and Excel when required.
- Monthly Summary Report on ART, TBT, PMTCT, HTS, PrEP.

DATA ANALYST INTERN | Quantum Analytics Nigeria 2023

March - July

Duties

- Data Preparation: data collection, data cleaning, data structuring and modelling, and data consolidation using Excel, and Power BI.
- Using Data Analysis Expressions (DAX) on Power BI to create calculated columns, new and quick measures, and custom tables.
- Using different Excel functions and formulars such as SUM, CLEAN, TRIM, AVERAGE, VLOOKUP, for data cleaning and performing calculations.
- Using Structured Query Language (SQL) to create tables, insert values into tables, and clean data in Relational Databases.
- Generating insights and findings from datasets, and visualizing those insights on dashboards using Power BI and Excel
- Live recording and presentation of prepared dashboards via zoom.

Data Entry Officer | Akidi Fish Farm, Girei, Adamawa State Jan 2020 - Aug 2021 Duties

- Compiled and sorted hard copy of source data regarding expenses and management of fish farm
- Reviewed the source data for incomplete or inaccurate information
- Typed/entered the source data into a spreadsheet on MS Excel, and on MS Word
- Maintained accurate records of the information entered by constantly updating existing data with new information provided.
- Sorted and organized hardcopy of source data after entering the data, to ensure it is not lost

Enumerator | Women Advocate Research and Documentation Center (WARDC) July 2019

Duties

- Executed a Survey on Gender-Based Violence (GBV) within the vicinity of Modibbo Adama University, using Google forms, and SurveyCTO
- Issuing out questionnaires to respondents willing to partake in the survey.
- Interpreting interview questions to respondents to ensure accurate responses
- Compiling, recording and transfer of information obtained to the organization database

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Technology (B. Tech) in Microbiology, Modibbo Adama University, Yola, September 2021

SKILLS

- Preparing, compiling, and sorting data for data entry
- · Excellent use of standard office software such as MS Excel, MS Word, and Power Point
- Good use of data entry software such as Excel, LAMISplus.
- Data Cleaning and Transformation
- Good use of Excel, SQL, and Power BI for analysing data
- Knowledge of statistical methods and techniques for data analysis.
- Data Visualization
- Database Management
- Strong analytical and problem-solving skills
- Data Privacy and Security
- · Ability to work under minimal supervision
- · Excellent communication and presentation skills
- Time Management skills
- · Attention to Details
- Collaborative skills

REFEREE

Available on Request